<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ml on Saikat Kumar Dey</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/categories/ml/</link><description>Recent content in ml on Saikat Kumar Dey</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</managingEditor><webMaster>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 13:06:10 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saikatkumardey.com/categories/ml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Training Image Classification Models with scikeras</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/scikeras/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 13:06:10 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/scikeras/</guid><description>Introduction to scikeras Scikeras is a powerful tool that allows users to combine the capabilities of TensorFlow and scikit-learn in order to train deep learning models. By using scikeras, users can take advantage of the strengths of both TensorFlow and scikit-learn, and benefit from the ease of use and flexibility of scikit-learn&amp;rsquo;s API.
In this blog post, we will demonstrate how to use scikeras to train a model using a large dataset of images stored on disk.</description></item><item><title>Accuracy Is a Poor evaluation Metric</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/accuracy-is-a-poor-error-metric/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 10:25:15 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/accuracy-is-a-poor-error-metric/</guid><description>For classification problems, something like Cross-entropy is a good metric for minimizing your model&amp;rsquo;s loss. However, we need something easier to convey to the stakeholders. Accuracy is a very easy way to show our model performances. The caveat? Accuracy would be misleading for imbalanced classes.
Here&amp;rsquo;s why.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say that you&amp;rsquo;ve built a model for detecting cancer. Here&amp;rsquo;s how the confusion matrix would look like for a dataset on cancer cases.</description></item><item><title>Deep Neural Networks for YouTube Recommendations</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/deep-nn-for-youtube-recommendations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 09:59:03 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/deep-nn-for-youtube-recommendations/</guid><description>YouTube has 100m+ daily active users who consume more than a billion hours&amp;rsquo; worth of content every day. 100s of hours of videos are uploaded every second. At that scale, recommending personalized videos is a colossal task.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always wondered how YouTube is always able to come up with relevant recommendations that kept me hooked! I found a very interesting paper on Deep Neural networks for YouTube Recommendations. In this post, I will summarise the key ideas.</description></item><item><title>Predictive Model Performance Online and Offline Eval</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/predictive-model-performance-online-and-offline-eval/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 09:57:00 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/predictive-model-performance-online-and-offline-eval/</guid><description>Evaluation is an important topic in every machine learning project. There are offline metrics that we compute on the historical data. It&amp;rsquo;s supposed to provide us an indication of our model performance on real data. However, we often see a discrepancy in offline vs online performance.
In Predictive model performance: Offline and online evaluations, the authors investigate the offline/online model performance on advertisement data from Bing Search Engine.
Key takeaways Evaluation metrics are important since it guides what the model optimizes on.</description></item></channel></rss>