<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Saikat Kumar Dey</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/</link><description>Saikat Kumar Dey</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 19:26:47 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saikatkumardey.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Walking helps you solve difficult bugs</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/14-walk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 19:26:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/14-walk/</guid><description>&lt;p>How do you solve a difficult bug?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Write the problem down.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Read it aloud.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go for a walk.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>When you let your mind wander, magic happens. Taking your conscious mind off a problem allows your mind to figure out non-linear solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where else could I apply this?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Brave Dark Mode</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/13-brave-dark-mode/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 12:09:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/13-brave-dark-mode/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dark mode is a must these days, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not all browsers support it by default.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The option for most of us is to use an extension. I am apprehensive about using an extension due to privacy concerns.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, how do I enable dark mode in brave?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Simply go to &lt;code>brave://flags/#enable-force-dark&lt;/code> and &amp;ldquo;Enable&amp;rdquo; it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CS 329s - Machine Learning Systems Design</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/12-cs-329/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 21:43:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/12-cs-329/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is going to be a super-short post, as I want to post a daily note here. :D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Discovered &lt;a href="https://stanford-cs329s.github.io/">CS 329s&lt;/a>, taught by &lt;a href="https://huyenchip.com/">Chip Huyen&lt;/a> at Stanford.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Going by the &lt;a href="https://stanford-cs329s.github.io/syllabus.html">syllabus&lt;/a> and a quick look through the content, this looks like an amazing resource for Machine Learning Engineers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I plan to audit the course and share my learnings here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are indeed lucky to have such great content out there, for absolutely free.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Accuracy Is a Poor evaluation Metric</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/essays/accuracy-is-a-poor-error-metric/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 10:25:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/essays/accuracy-is-a-poor-error-metric/</guid><description>&lt;p>For classification problems, something like Cross-entropy is a good metric for minimizing your model&amp;rsquo;s loss.
However, we need something easier to convey to the stakeholders.
Accuracy is a very easy way to show our model performances. The caveat? Accuracy would be misleading for imbalanced classes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s why.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s say that you&amp;rsquo;ve built a model for detecting cancer.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how the confusion matrix would look like for a dataset on cancer cases.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Predicted Cancer&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Predicted cancer-free&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Actual cancer cases&lt;/td>
&lt;td>10 (TP)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>5 (FN)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Actual cancer-free cases&lt;/td>
&lt;td>150 (FP)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>800 (TN)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>The dataset has 950 cancer-free patients and 15 patients with cancer.
The accuracy of the model = fraction of correct predictions = (10 + 800) / (10 + 5 + 150 + 800) = 0.84.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, the cancer cases are quite rare, so it barely has any effect on the accuracy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the model had predicted every case as cancer-free, the confusion matrix would look like the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Predicted Cancer&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Predicted cancer-free&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Actual cancer cases&lt;/td>
&lt;td>0 (TP)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>15 (FN)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Actual cancer-free cases&lt;/td>
&lt;td>0 (FP)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>950 (TN)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Accuracy = 950/(950 + 15) = 0.984%.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is not what we want to report to our stakeholders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are our options?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In such cases with class imbalance, we usually look at &lt;em>precision&lt;/em> and &lt;em>recall&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Precision&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>precision = TP/(TP + FP)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Precision is &lt;em>out of all the cancer diagnosis made by the model, how many of them actually have cancer&lt;/em>. In the first case, model predicted 165 cases as having cancer but only 15 of them actually had cancer. So, the precision is 15/165 which is quite low!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Recall&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>recall = TP/(TP+FN)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Recall is &lt;em>out of all the actual cancer cases, how many could the model detect?&lt;/em>
In the first case, model detected 15 out of 20 cancer cases. So, the recall is 15/20 = 0.75. That&amp;rsquo;s not bad!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our objective is to detect as many cancer cases as we can (TP) while minimizing the false diagnosis of cancer (FP). In other words, we want to have high recall with high precision.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All of these metrics rely on the probability threshold chosen to classify each sample as having cancer or not. If prediction probability &amp;gt; threshold, predict cancer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, if you choose 0.9 as the threshold, you might only classify cases where the model is highly confident ie, high precision. However, you might miss out on many cases at that threshold ie, low recall. Instead, if you keep 0.1 as the threshold, you might capture all the cancer cases but you&amp;rsquo;d be scaring a lot of other cancer-free patients with misdiagnosis as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By varying the probability threshold, you could check the trade-off between precision &amp;amp; recall, also called the precision-recall curve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes, precision &amp;amp; recall are combined together into one metric, called F1 score.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>F1 = 2 / (1/precision + 1/recall)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s another variant of the precision-recall curve which is agnostic to the probability threshold selected. It&amp;rsquo;s called the ROC curve (Receiver Operating Characteristics). The area under the curve (AUC) is demonstrative of the overall model performance. AUC is useful to know how well the model is in classifying both the classes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Conclusion&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Do not use accuracy metric when there&amp;rsquo;s a class imbalance.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use F1 or ROC-AUC instead.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Reference&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/practical-machine-learning/9781098102357/">Practical Machine Learning for Computer Vision&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precision_and_recall">Precision Recall&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Receiver_operating_characteristic">ROC Curve&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>C1: Reliable Scalable and Maintainable Applications</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/series/1-reliable-scalable-and-maintainable-applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 23:19:39 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/series/1-reliable-scalable-and-maintainable-applications/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Applications today are data-intensive as opposed to compute-intensive.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Standard building blocks of data-intensive applications
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Store data in &lt;em>databases&lt;/em> to make searching easier.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Speed up reads by storing them in &lt;em>caches&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Full-text search using &lt;em>search indexes&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Async data handling via &lt;em>stream processing&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>crunch large amount of data via &lt;em>batch processing&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For each building blocks mentioned above, there are many different options available to us. It could be difficult to know how to combine the tools as per our requirement.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="thinking-about-data-systems">Thinking about data systems&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Three important concerns in most software systems:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Reliability: system should continue to work correctly even in the face of adversity&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scalability: system should be able to handle growth in traffic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Maintainability: different people should be able to work on the system productively.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="reliability">Reliability&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Reliability means, &amp;ldquo;continuing to work correctly, even when things go wrong&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Systems that anticipate faults and can cope with them are called fault-tolerant or resilient.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fault is different from failure. Fault means that a part of the system doesn&amp;rsquo;t work as intended, failure means the entire system stops working altogether. Our objective is to ensure that a fault doesn&amp;rsquo;t lead to failure. As they say, prevention is better than cure!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reliability is important not just for critical applications like nuclear power plants &amp;amp; air traffic controls but for non-critical applications (like, say a photo sharing app). Why? We have a responsibility to our users.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Only situation where we could sacrifice reliability is when we&amp;rsquo;re building prototypes or minimizing operational costs for a service with a narrow margin. However, we should be aware of when we&amp;rsquo;re cutting corners.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="scalability">Scalability&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We use the term &lt;em>scalability&lt;/em> to describe a system&amp;rsquo;s ability to cope with increased load.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If our system grows in a particular way, what are our options for coping with the growth? How can we add computing resources to handle additional load?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Before we address growth questions, we need to describe the current load on the system.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What is load?
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>load can be defined using load parameters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>load parameters depend on the architecture of the system. It could be
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>requests per second for a web server&lt;/li>
&lt;li>reads:writes in a database&lt;/li>
&lt;li>concurrent users in a chat room&lt;/li>
&lt;li>hit rate on a cache, etc&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Example: Distribution of followers per user is a key load parameter for scalability of twitter since it determines the fan-out load.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>fan-out: number of requests to other services that we need to make to serve one incoming request.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>context: each user follows many people and each user is followed by many people.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>for simple users with few followers/following few people, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to join different tables to display user&amp;rsquo;s timeline.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>for &amp;ldquo;celebrities&amp;rdquo; with millions of followers, the simple approach won&amp;rsquo;t work. Celebrity tweets for the followers of a celebrity are cached in their respective timeline &amp;ldquo;caches&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>twitter uses a hybrid approach for treating different types of users.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="describing-performance">Describing Performance&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>How to investigate the impact of load increase on your system?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>When you increase a load parameter and keep the system resources unchanged, how is the performance of the system affected?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When you increase a load parameter, how much do you need to increase the system resources to keep the performance unchanged?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We need a performance measure to answer these questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For web services, usually &amp;ldquo;response time&amp;rdquo; is of interest. Often times, &amp;ldquo;average response time&amp;rdquo; is stated which is not helpful - it doesn&amp;rsquo;t tell us how many users experienced the delay. Use percentiles instead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To figure out how bad your outliers are, look at 95th, 99th and 99.9th percentiles aka p95, p99 and p999.
If the 95th percentile response time is 1.5 sec, that means 95 out of 100 requests take less than 1.5 secs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When several backend calls are needed to serve a request, it takes just a single slow request to slow down the entire end-user request.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="approaches-for-coping-with-load">Approaches for coping with load&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>scaling up aka vertical scaling means upgrading to a more powerful machine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>scaling out aka horizontal scaling means distributing the load across several smaller machines. This is also called shared-nothing architecture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A good architecture is a pragmatic mixture of both.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elastic systems automatically add computing resources when they detect a load increase. Such systems are good when the load is highly unpredictable but manually scaled systems are simpler.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s no magic scaling sauce. The architecture depends on the problem at hand - volume of reads/writes, volume of data to store, etc. For example, a system that handles 100k RPS, each 1KB in size is very different from a system that handles 3 RPS, each 2 GB in size.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before scaling, think about which operations are common and which ones are rare. Figure out the load parameters. As a startup with an unproven product idea, you should be able to iterate quickly rather than trying to scale some hypothetical feature load that might come in the future. See &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PE4gwstWhmc">How We&amp;rsquo;ve Scaled Dropbox&lt;/a> for some inspiration!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Best of Reddit</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/11-best-of-reddit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 21:22:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/11-best-of-reddit/</guid><description>&lt;p>I love reddit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s so much fun to learn from people from all over the world who are kind enough to unconditionally share their experiences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IMO, the best resources are buried deep inside reddit comments that could be discovered if you&amp;rsquo;re hungry enough!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are the best content I discovered so far:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/kaidomac/">r/kaidomac&lt;/a>: subreddit for aggregating knowledge from user &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/kaidomac/">u/kaidomac&lt;/a>, managed by the author himself. Some of his best posts:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/kaidomac/comments/rqyk6a/the_wpp_approach_to_planning_out_your_day/">The WPP Approach to planning out your day
&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/IWantToLearn/comments/qg3thy/deleted_by_user/hi5ex16/?context=3">Life planning&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/bodyweightfitness/comments/d0rxv6/muscle_growth/ezebxg9/?context=3">Macros tutorial&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/theXeffect/">r/theXeffect&lt;/a>: People here are on a 50-day journey to create/break one or more habits by simply making a 7x7 grid on a card and crossing off each day with a fat-ass felt marker, because your willpower is like a muscle, and it gets stronger and stronger as you exercise it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I will continue to update this as I discover new items.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Life Is Short and So Is This Book</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/10-life-is-short-and-so-is-this-book/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 23:35:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/10-life-is-short-and-so-is-this-book/</guid><description>&lt;p>The best part about the book is that it&amp;rsquo;s short and isn&amp;rsquo;t filled with fluff.
Almost everything in this book is common sense found in most self-help books.
But common sense isn&amp;rsquo;t common right? We need reminders to keep us on our path. This is the book that aggregates the advice found in most self-help books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are some of the points that resonated with me:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>people who are most productive tend to say no to things that are unimportant to them and focus on what they believe matters.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The fear of death follows from the fear of life. A man who lives fully is prepared to die at any time.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I’ve found the only way people have the stamina to outwork others, year after year, is when they love what they do.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ideally, you want a job you’d do even if you weren’t paid to do it. That’s not an economic reality for most of us, but it’s the right goal to shoot for. If you can get paid to do what you perceive as play, you have a great job.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To make changes in your life, focus on taking small steps in the right direction. Whether you want to change your health, your job, or your relationship, you can’t do it overnight. And you can’t become great at anything without a lot of repeated practice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to start a business, write a book, invent some new device, learn to play an instrument, get better at a sport, or be a good parent. Remember: take small steps. They work. Big steps often don’t. Over time, small steps add up, and you end up in a different place.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Secret of Success by Mark Twain</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/9-secret-of-success-by-mark-twain/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:24:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/9-secret-of-success-by-mark-twain/</guid><description>&lt;p>The secret of getting ahead is getting started. The secret of getting started is breaking your complex overwhelming tasks into small manageable tasks, and starting on the first one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>pre-commit hooks</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/8-pre-commit-hooks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 23:34:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/8-pre-commit-hooks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Code smells should be identified before they&amp;rsquo;re pushed committed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://pre-commit.com/">pre-commit&lt;/a> hooks allow you to define a standard for your codebase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry if the latest PR follows the &lt;a href="https://peps.python.org/pep-0008/">PEP 8&lt;/a> conventions. Simply add a &lt;a href="https://github.com/PyCQA/flake8">flake8&lt;/a> hook to your pre-commit config file. Even better, add a &lt;a href="https://github.com/psf/black">black&lt;/a> config to ensure your code formatting is PEP 8 compliant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Accidentally added a large-file to staging? No problem, pre-commit hooks will point it out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Forgot to remove debug statements in your latest patch? pre-commit hooks got you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Forgot to add a huge file from staging? pre-commit hook will help you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes we commit massive jupyter notebooks (due to output) which makes the repository heavy &amp;amp; difficult to work with. pre-commit hooks could automatically strip the output from our notebooks before you commit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>pre-commit hooks will prevent anyone from committing changes to your code-base with such known issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It will allow the reviewers to focus on core contribution of a pull-request instead of trivial issues which could be avoided.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are you waiting for ? Go get yourself some &lt;a href="https://pre-commit.com/">pre-commit&lt;/a> hooks for your freshly minted repository!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Relax</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/6-relax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 10:43:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/6-relax/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some days, you&amp;rsquo;ll be pulled into so many different directions that you won&amp;rsquo;t know what to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take a step back and breathe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nothing is more important than inner peace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Focus on one and only one thing and finish that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No need to multitask. Delegate it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>