<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Saikat Kumar Dey</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/</link><description>Recent content on Saikat Kumar Dey</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</managingEditor><webMaster>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saikatkumardey.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Minimalist Habit Tracking App for Myself Using SwiftUI</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/2023/july/minimalist-habit-tracking-ios-app/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/2023/july/minimalist-habit-tracking-ios-app/</guid><description>Introduction I recently (re)read Atomic Habits by James Clear which highlights how small, consistent habits can lead to remarkable results over time. The book motivated me to be more intentional about building good habits into my routines.
I looked around at existing habit tracking apps on the App Store but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find one that was simple and minimalistic enough for my needs. Many were bloated with unnecessary gamification, social sharing, subscriptions, etc.</description></item><item><title>How to Live on 24 Hours a Day by Arnold Bennett</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/how-to-live-on-24-hours-a-day/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 12:37:57 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/how-to-live-on-24-hours-a-day/</guid><description>Life moves fast, my friends - faster than we realize. Before you know it, your days and years will be gone. Each moment is a gift, so how are you gonna spend it? Floating along or diving in? Arnold Bennett says too many of us squander our time on distraction and leisure. But life&amp;rsquo;s meant for living! Don&amp;rsquo;t just sit there - get up and seize the day.
Follow Your Curiosity and Passion We&amp;rsquo;ve only got so much time in this world, so pursue what fires you up!</description></item><item><title>I summarised a 3 hour long youtube video using LLMs</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/claude+langchain+youtube/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/claude+langchain+youtube/</guid><description>I used Langchain + Claude to summarise Sam Altman&amp;rsquo;s testimony to the US Senate on AI. The video is 3 hours long and the transcript has about 30k+ tokens. I used Langchain to extract the transcript and Claude to summarise it. The result is a 1 page summary of the key points from the video. I have included the summary, code, and prompt below.
Tech:
Langchain to extract the transcript from YouTube Claude (claude-instant-v1-100k) to summarise the transcript Prompt &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34; Please write a professional summary with a beginning, middle, and end based on the video transcript.</description></item><item><title>From Rules to Vectors: How NLP Changed Over Time</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/nlp-from-rules-to-vector/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 01:21:37 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/nlp-from-rules-to-vector/</guid><description>This is a quick summary of Manning’s article on the history and future of natural language processing and foundation models.
Manning divides NLP history into four eras based on different approaches: Machine translation: simple word-level translation with rules and lookups (1950-1969). Rule-based systems: hand-built systems that handle syntax and reference with linguistic theories and knowledge-based AI (1970-1992). Empirical machine learning models: statistical models that learn from data with labels or annotations for specific tasks or domains (1993-2012).</description></item><item><title>Side-Projects</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/projects/</guid><description>Bots Here are a list of fun bots that I have built on Poe. I will keep on adding more bots to this list.
GitaBot - Get solutions from Gita to your problems
TheMichaelScott - Talk to Michael Scott from The Office
ELI5Bot - Let AI explain a topic as if you were 5 years old
TwentyQuestions - Play 20 questions with AI
Converso Converso is a chatbot that matches your mood.</description></item><item><title>Beyond F1: using the Fbeta_score for better model evaluation</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/fbeta/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 21:08:28 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/fbeta/</guid><description>Hey everyone!
Today I want to talk about a little-known evaluation metric: Fbeta_score.
If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with machine learning, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard of F1 score. It&amp;rsquo;s a common metric used to evaluate the performance of classification models, and it&amp;rsquo;s defined as the harmonic mean of precision and recall. This is great for a lot of tasks, but there are some situations where F1 score might not be the best choice.</description></item><item><title>Solving Class Imbalance with Focal Loss</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/focal-loss/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 20:49:34 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/focal-loss/</guid><description>Class imbalance occurs when the number of observations in one or more classes is significantly different from the number of observations in other classes. This can lead to poor model performance, particularly when the minority class is important to predict accurately.
Focal loss is a loss function that down-weights the contribution of well-classified examples and focuses on hard-to-classify examples. This can help to improve the performance of a machine learning model when dealing with class imbalance.</description></item><item><title>Mastering Common Patterns to Solve Leetcode Problems</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/leetcode-patterns/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 10:25:29 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/leetcode-patterns/</guid><description>In this post, I will introduce you to 14 important patterns that can help you solve most of the problems on Leetcode. I will provide a template for each pattern to help you quickly apply it to a problem, as well as a list of important problems to practice with. By the end of this post, you will have a powerful set of tools to enhance your problem-solving skills on Leetcode and beyond.</description></item><item><title>How to love what you do?</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/15/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 09:40:42 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/15/</guid><description>Finding the work you love can often seem like a daunting task, but there&amp;rsquo;s no secret ingredient to it. Instead, the key is to simply start producing. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a writer, an artist, a musician, or anything else, the most important thing is to just get started and begin creating.
At first, it&amp;rsquo;s okay to focus on quantity rather than quality. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about making everything perfect from the beginning – just keep producing and putting yourself out there.</description></item><item><title>Training Image Classification Models with scikeras</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/scikeras/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 13:06:10 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/scikeras/</guid><description>Introduction to scikeras Scikeras is a powerful tool that allows users to combine the capabilities of TensorFlow and scikit-learn in order to train deep learning models. By using scikeras, users can take advantage of the strengths of both TensorFlow and scikit-learn, and benefit from the ease of use and flexibility of scikit-learn&amp;rsquo;s API.
In this blog post, we will demonstrate how to use scikeras to train a model using a large dataset of images stored on disk.</description></item><item><title>Walking helps you solve difficult bugs</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/14-walk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 19:26:47 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/14-walk/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re a programmer, you know how frustrating it can be to come across a difficult bug. These pesky little issues can derail your entire day, leaving you feeling frustrated and stuck. But did you know that going for a walk can actually help you solve these difficult bugs?
It&amp;rsquo;s true – walking helps you think better. When you&amp;rsquo;re stuck on a problem, your mind tends to get stuck in a rut, going over the same information again and again.</description></item><item><title>Brave Dark Mode</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/13-brave-dark-mode/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 12:09:19 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/13-brave-dark-mode/</guid><description>Dark mode is all the rage these days, and for good reason. Not only does it look sleek and stylish, but it can also help to reduce eye strain and save battery life on devices with OLED screens. But not all browsers support dark mode by default, leaving many users to rely on extensions to enable the feature.
However, using an extension can come with its own set of challenges. Some users may be hesitant to use an extension due to privacy concerns, or because they simply don&amp;rsquo;t want to clutter their browser with additional software.</description></item><item><title>Accuracy Is a Poor evaluation Metric</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/accuracy-is-a-poor-error-metric/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 10:25:15 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/accuracy-is-a-poor-error-metric/</guid><description>For classification problems, something like Cross-entropy is a good metric for minimizing your model&amp;rsquo;s loss. However, we need something easier to convey to the stakeholders. Accuracy is a very easy way to show our model performances. The caveat? Accuracy would be misleading for imbalanced classes.
Here&amp;rsquo;s why.
Let&amp;rsquo;s say that you&amp;rsquo;ve built a model for detecting cancer. Here&amp;rsquo;s how the confusion matrix would look like for a dataset on cancer cases.</description></item><item><title>C1: Reliable Scalable and Maintainable Applications</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/1-reliable-scalable-and-maintainable-applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/1-reliable-scalable-and-maintainable-applications/</guid><description>Intro Applications today are data-intensive as opposed to compute-intensive. Standard building blocks of data-intensive applications Store data in databases to make searching easier. Speed up reads by storing them in caches Full-text search using search indexes Async data handling via stream processing crunch large amount of data via batch processing For each building blocks mentioned above, there are many different options available to us. It could be difficult to know how to combine the tools as per our requirement.</description></item><item><title>Best of Reddit</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/11-best-of-reddit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 21:22:53 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/11-best-of-reddit/</guid><description>I love reddit.
It&amp;rsquo;s so much fun to learn from people from all over the world who are kind enough to unconditionally share their experiences.
IMO, the best resources are buried deep inside reddit comments that could be discovered if you&amp;rsquo;re hungry enough!
Here are the best content I discovered so far:
r/kaidomac: subreddit for aggregating knowledge from user u/kaidomac, managed by the author himself. Some of his best posts: - The WPP Approach to planning out your day - Life planning - Macros tutorial r/theXeffect: People here are on a 50-day journey to create/break one or more habits by simply making a 7x7 grid on a card and crossing off each day with a fat-ass felt marker, because your willpower is like a muscle, and it gets stronger and stronger as you exercise it.</description></item><item><title>Life Is Short and So Is This Book</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/10-life-is-short-and-so-is-this-book/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 23:35:55 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/10-life-is-short-and-so-is-this-book/</guid><description>The best part about the book is that it&amp;rsquo;s short and isn&amp;rsquo;t filled with fluff. Almost everything in this book is common sense found in most self-help books. But common sense isn&amp;rsquo;t common right? We need reminders to keep us on our path. This is the book that aggregates the advice found in most self-help books.
Here are some of the points that resonated with me:
people who are most productive tend to say no to things that are unimportant to them and focus on what they believe matters.</description></item><item><title>Secret of Success by Mark Twain</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/9-secret-of-success-by-mark-twain/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:24:09 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/9-secret-of-success-by-mark-twain/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s world, it can often feel like there are so many things to do and so little time to do them. It can be overwhelming to think about all the tasks and responsibilities that we have, and it can be difficult to know where to even begin. But as the famous author Marc Twain once said,
The secret of getting ahead is getting started. The secret of getting started is breaking your complex overwhelming tasks into small manageable tasks, and starting on the first one.</description></item><item><title>pre-commit hooks</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/8-pre-commit-hooks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 23:34:18 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/8-pre-commit-hooks/</guid><description>Code smells should be identified before they&amp;rsquo;re pushed committed.
pre-commit hooks allow you to define a standard for your codebase.
You don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry if the latest PR follows the PEP 8 conventions. Simply add a flake8 hook to your pre-commit config file. Even better, add a black config to ensure your code formatting is PEP 8 compliant.
Accidentally added a large-file to staging? No problem, pre-commit hooks will point it out.</description></item><item><title>The Importance of Focusing on One Thing at a Time</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/6-relax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 10:43:27 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/6-relax/</guid><description>When it feels like the world is pulling us in a million different directions, it can be easy to become overwhelmed and stressed. We may feel like we need to multitask and tackle everything at once, but this can often be counterproductive. Instead, it&amp;rsquo;s important to take a step back and focus on one thing at a time.
There&amp;rsquo;s a common misconception that multitasking is a sign of productivity. In reality, multitasking can actually decrease our productivity and make it more difficult for us to complete tasks effectively.</description></item><item><title>Own Your Content</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/5-own-your-content/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:54:52 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/5-own-your-content/</guid><description>Over a decade or so, I have written blog posts in different platforms scattered all over the Internet.
What happens when those companies go out of business? All of your data would be lost unless you&amp;rsquo;ve kept a backup.
Derek Sivers recommends keeping your content on text files. Text files are cross-platform &amp;amp; easy to manage. You could easily convert them to the format of your choice. You do not need the internet to access your files.</description></item><item><title>Never Too Late: The Inspiring Story of Van Gogh</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/4-never-too-late/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:40:51 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/4-never-too-late/</guid><description>Have you ever felt like it&amp;rsquo;s too late to pursue your dreams? Perhaps you feel like you&amp;rsquo;re too old, or you&amp;rsquo;ve missed your chance. If so, it&amp;rsquo;s time to reconsider. The story of Van Gogh is a perfect example of how it&amp;rsquo;s never too late to start something and become world-class at it.
Van Gogh is one of the most famous and celebrated artists in history, known for his beautiful and unique paintings.</description></item><item><title>The Power of Consistent Investing</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/3-keep-investing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 21:03:26 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/3-keep-investing/</guid><description>If you have money to spare, it&amp;rsquo;s always a good idea to invest it. Investing can help your money grow and provide financial security for the future. But where should you invest your money? And how can you make the most of your investments? Here are some key tips to keep in mind.
First and foremost, don&amp;rsquo;t try to pick individual stocks. Unless you have a lot of experience and expertise in the stock market, it&amp;rsquo;s generally not a good idea to try and pick individual stocks.</description></item><item><title>What I'm doing now</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/now/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:58:39 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/now/</guid><description>Work I am a Senior Data Scientist at Gojek. I work on building and deploying machine learning models at scale.
Side Projects I am currently tinkering with language models and their applications. See a list of fun projects. Recently, I launched Converso, a telegram chatbot powered by GPT-3 capable of having conversations with you in 30+ personalities.
I am also learning flutter to prototype some app ideas.
Learning I am currently deepening my understanding of large language models (LLM).</description></item><item><title>Hosting on Github Pages</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/2-hosting-on-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:44:31 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/2-hosting-on-github-pages/</guid><description>Make sure you have a CNAME file with your custom website in it. Make sure that you have it in your &amp;ldquo;gh-pages&amp;rdquo; branch.
Ensure that you have configured the CNAME in your DNS provider&amp;rsquo;s console. I am using Cloudflare. So, I have configured 2 records
CNAME to redirect &amp;ldquo;saikatkumardey.com&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;saikatkumardey.github.io&amp;rdquo;. CNAME to redirect &amp;ldquo;www.saikatkumardey.com&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;saikatkumardey.github.io&amp;rdquo;. Make sure that you set the Source of your Github Pages site to be built from the gh-pages branch.</description></item><item><title>The Benefits and Challenges of Remote Work</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/1-remote-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 08:29:24 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/1-remote-work/</guid><description>Remote work has become increasingly popular in recent years, and for good reason. There are many benefits to working from home, including the ability to be with your family, save money on rent and commute, and have more control over your work environment. But there are also some challenges that come with remote work, and it&amp;rsquo;s important to be aware of both the benefits and challenges.
One of the biggest benefits of remote work is the ability to do &amp;ldquo;deep work.</description></item><item><title>Building Pandas Dataframes From Ndarrays</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/building-pandas-dataframes-from-ndarrays/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 10:06:23 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/building-pandas-dataframes-from-ndarrays/</guid><description>At work, I have to switch between numpy &amp;amp; pandas depending on the computational needs. Numpy is faster. Pandas is easier to work with.
One of the tasks I&amp;rsquo;ve faced often was to convert a 3-dimensional ndarray to a pandas dataframe. I will share my preferred technique in this post today.
For the purpose of this exercise, I&amp;rsquo;ll generate dummy sales data for a retail company. The dimensions include products, locations, and sales.</description></item><item><title>Show Your Work by Austin Kleon</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/book-notes-show-your-work-by-austin-kleon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 10:01:12 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/book-notes-show-your-work-by-austin-kleon/</guid><description>“Find a scenius, pay attention to what others are sharing, and then start taking note of what they’re not sharing. Be on the lookout for voids that you can fill with your own efforts, no matter how bad they are at first. Don’t worry, for now, about how you’ll make money or a career off it. Forget about being an expert or a professional, and wear your amateurism (your heart, your love) on your sleeve.</description></item><item><title>Anything You Want by Derek Sivers</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/book-notes-anything-you-want-by-derek-sivers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 10:00:34 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/book-notes-anything-you-want-by-derek-sivers/</guid><description>Don&amp;rsquo;t be on your deathbed someday, having squandered your one chance at life, full of regret because you pursued little distractions instead of big dreams.
Once you&amp;rsquo;ve got a hit, suddenly all the locked doors open wide. People love the hit so much that it seems to promote itself. Instead of trying to create demand, you&amp;rsquo;re managing the huge demand
Success comes from persistently improving and inventing, not from persistently doing what&amp;rsquo;s not working.</description></item><item><title>A Simplified Implementation of Quicksort</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/a-simplified-implementation-of-quicksort/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 09:59:45 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/a-simplified-implementation-of-quicksort/</guid><description>Quicksort is a beautiful algorithm. It&amp;rsquo;s considered the fastest sorting algorithm in practice. Most implementations I&amp;rsquo;ve seen online are complicated. This post will demonstrate a simple implementation that trades space complexity for readability.
How does quicksort work? 3 steps.
Choose a pivot element. Partition: Put all elements smaller than the pivot in a smaller array, (say, smaller_subarray). Put all elements greater than the pivot in another array (say, greater_subarray). Recurse &amp;amp; Merge: Recursively sort the smaller and greater sub-arrays.</description></item><item><title>Deep Neural Networks for YouTube Recommendations</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/deep-nn-for-youtube-recommendations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 09:59:03 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/deep-nn-for-youtube-recommendations/</guid><description>YouTube has 100m+ daily active users who consume more than a billion hours&amp;rsquo; worth of content every day. 100s of hours of videos are uploaded every second. At that scale, recommending personalized videos is a colossal task.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always wondered how YouTube is always able to come up with relevant recommendations that kept me hooked! I found a very interesting paper on Deep Neural networks for YouTube Recommendations. In this post, I will summarise the key ideas.</description></item><item><title>Predictive Model Performance Online and Offline Eval</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/predictive-model-performance-online-and-offline-eval/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 09:57:00 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/predictive-model-performance-online-and-offline-eval/</guid><description>Evaluation is an important topic in every machine learning project. There are offline metrics that we compute on the historical data. It&amp;rsquo;s supposed to provide us an indication of our model performance on real data. However, we often see a discrepancy in offline vs online performance.
In Predictive model performance: Offline and online evaluations, the authors investigate the offline/online model performance on advertisement data from Bing Search Engine.
Key takeaways Evaluation metrics are important since it guides what the model optimizes on.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/contact/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>