<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>daily on Saikat Kumar Dey</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/categories/daily/</link><description>daily</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 11:15:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saikatkumardey.com/categories/daily/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Own Your Content</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/5-own-your-content/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:54:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/5-own-your-content/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over a decade or so, I have written blog posts in different platforms scattered all over the Internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What happens when those companies go out of business? All of your data would be lost unless you&amp;rsquo;ve kept a backup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sive.rs/plaintext">Derek Sivers&lt;/a> recommends keeping your content on text files. Text files are cross-platform &amp;amp; easy to manage. You could easily convert them to the format of your choice. You do not need the internet to access your files. Sure, online platforms might provide a better UI. However, you don&amp;rsquo;t really need the distraction while putting down your raw thoughts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have many ideas jotted down across multiple platforms, apps and yes, text files on my devices. From now on, I will use this website as my own digital garden to keep it all. I will start gathering all my posts from the past scattered across different platforms and share them in this space.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Never Too Late: The Inspiring Story of Van Gogh</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/4-never-too-late/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:40:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/4-never-too-late/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have you ever felt like it&amp;rsquo;s too late to pursue your dreams? Perhaps you feel like you&amp;rsquo;re too old, or you&amp;rsquo;ve missed your chance. If so, it&amp;rsquo;s time to reconsider. The story of Van Gogh is a perfect example of how it&amp;rsquo;s never too late to start something and become world-class at it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Van Gogh is one of the most famous and celebrated artists in history, known for his beautiful and unique paintings. But did you know that he didn&amp;rsquo;t start painting seriously until he was 27 years old? That&amp;rsquo;s right, it was well into his adult life before Van Gogh began pursuing his passion for art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Despite starting later in life, Van Gogh was incredibly productive. Over the course of just 10 years, he created over 2,000 artworks. And most of those were created in the last two years of his life. In just a short amount of time, Van Gogh was able to achieve incredible success and make a lasting impact on the world of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is proof that it&amp;rsquo;s never too late to start something and become world-class at it. If Van Gogh could do it, so can you. So don&amp;rsquo;t let age or any other perceived limitations hold you back. It&amp;rsquo;s never too late to pursue your dreams and make them a reality. Take inspiration from Van Gogh and start working towards your goals today. You never know what you might be capable of achieving.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Power of Consistent Investing</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/3-keep-investing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 21:03:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/3-keep-investing/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you have money to spare, it&amp;rsquo;s always a good idea to invest it. Investing can help your money grow and provide financial security for the future. But where should you invest your money? And how can you make the most of your investments? Here are some key tips to keep in mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First and foremost, don&amp;rsquo;t try to pick individual stocks. Unless you have a lot of experience and expertise in the stock market, it&amp;rsquo;s generally not a good idea to try and pick individual stocks. Instead, invest in index funds and ETFs. These types of investments are more diversified, which means they can help reduce the overall risk of your investment portfolio. And as the saying goes, &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t put all your eggs in one basket.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another important tip is to automate your investments. One of the best ways to do this is through a systematic investment plan (SIP). A SIP allows you to automatically invest a fixed amount of money at regular intervals. This can help you build a consistent investment strategy and take the emotion out of investing. Plus, it can be a convenient way to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re always investing, even when you&amp;rsquo;re busy with other things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s also important to remember that time in the market is more important than timing the market. In other words, it&amp;rsquo;s not about trying to predict when the market will go up or down. Instead, focus on building a long-term investment strategy that can help your money grow over time. And remember, the real fruit of your investments will be seen years later. So don&amp;rsquo;t be discouraged if you don&amp;rsquo;t see immediate results. Let compound interest do its thing and your investments can grow significantly over time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, don&amp;rsquo;t worry too much about the market. It&amp;rsquo;s natural to want to stay up-to-date on the latest market news and trends. But ultimately, your time is better spent focusing on being the best at what you do. And remember, when the market is down, it&amp;rsquo;s actually an opportunity to buy equity at a discount. So don&amp;rsquo;t let market fluctuations discourage you. Keep investing consistently and let your money grow over time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hosting on Github Pages</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/2-hosting-on-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:44:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/2-hosting-on-github-pages/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Make sure you have a &lt;a href="https://github.com/saikatkumardey/saikatkumardey.github.io/blob/main/CNAME">CNAME&lt;/a> file with your custom website in it. Make sure that you have it in your &amp;ldquo;gh-pages&amp;rdquo; branch.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ensure that you have configured the CNAME in your DNS provider&amp;rsquo;s console. I am using &lt;a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/">Cloudflare&lt;/a>. So, I have configured 2 records&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>CNAME to redirect &amp;ldquo;saikatkumardey.com&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;saikatkumardey.github.io&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CNAME to redirect &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://www.saikatkumardey.com">www.saikatkumardey.com&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;saikatkumardey.github.io&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Make sure that you set the Source of your Github Pages site to be built from the gh-pages branch. Go to Settings &amp;gt; Pages &amp;gt; Source. Check if it&amp;rsquo;s set to gh-pages. This caused me a lot of pain. It&amp;rsquo;s set to &amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo; by default.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>The Benefits and Challenges of Remote Work</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/1-remote-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 08:29:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/1-remote-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>Remote work has become increasingly popular in recent years, and for good reason. There are many benefits to working from home, including the ability to be with your family, save money on rent and commute, and have more control over your work environment. But there are also some challenges that come with remote work, and it&amp;rsquo;s important to be aware of both the benefits and challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the biggest benefits of remote work is the ability to do &amp;ldquo;deep work.&amp;rdquo; This is the idea of focusing on a single task for an extended period of time without interruptions. When you&amp;rsquo;re working from home, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to tune out notifications and distractions and focus on getting things done. This can be incredibly productive and can help you achieve more in less time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But there are also some challenges to remote work. For example, you don&amp;rsquo;t get to meet your team-mates regularly, which can make it more difficult to build trust and develop strong relationships. And when you&amp;rsquo;re not in the office, you may not feel as fully engaged with the company and its culture. Additionally, brainstorming and collaboration with your colleagues can be more difficult when you&amp;rsquo;re not in the same physical space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultimately, the key to making remote work successful is to find a balance between the benefits and challenges. A hybrid work set-up, where you work from home most of the time but also meet with your team regularly, can be a great way to achieve this balance. This way, you can enjoy the benefits of remote work while also staying connected with your colleagues and the company.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>