<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>books on Saikat Kumar Dey</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/categories/books/</link><description>books</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 23:35:55 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saikatkumardey.com/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Life Is Short and So Is This Book</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/10-life-is-short-and-so-is-this-book/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 23:35:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/10-life-is-short-and-so-is-this-book/</guid><description>&lt;p>The best part about the book is that it&amp;rsquo;s short and isn&amp;rsquo;t filled with fluff.
Almost everything in this book is common sense found in most self-help books.
But common sense isn&amp;rsquo;t common right? We need reminders to keep us on our path. This is the book that aggregates the advice found in most self-help books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are some of the points that resonated with me:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>people who are most productive tend to say no to things that are unimportant to them and focus on what they believe matters.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The fear of death follows from the fear of life. A man who lives fully is prepared to die at any time.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I’ve found the only way people have the stamina to outwork others, year after year, is when they love what they do.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ideally, you want a job you’d do even if you weren’t paid to do it. That’s not an economic reality for most of us, but it’s the right goal to shoot for. If you can get paid to do what you perceive as play, you have a great job.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To make changes in your life, focus on taking small steps in the right direction. Whether you want to change your health, your job, or your relationship, you can’t do it overnight. And you can’t become great at anything without a lot of repeated practice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to start a business, write a book, invent some new device, learn to play an instrument, get better at a sport, or be a good parent. Remember: take small steps. They work. Big steps often don’t. Over time, small steps add up, and you end up in a different place.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Show Your Work by Austin Kleon</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/essays/book-notes-show-your-work-by-austin-kleon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 10:01:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/essays/book-notes-show-your-work-by-austin-kleon/</guid><description>&lt;p>“Find a scenius, pay attention to what others are sharing, and then start taking note of what they’re not sharing. Be on the lookout for voids that you can fill with your own efforts, no matter how bad they are at first. Don’t worry, for now, about how you’ll make money or a career off it. Forget about being an expert or a professional, and wear your amateurism (your heart, your love) on your sleeve. Share what you love, and the people who love the same things will find you.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“When George Lucas was a teenager, he almost died in a car accident. He decided “every day now is an extra day,” dedicated himself to film, and went on to direct Star Wars.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I realized I was going to die,” he says. “And when that gets into your mind . . . it utterly changed me . . . I thought, I’m not going to sit here and wait for things to happen, I’m going to make them happen, and if people think I’m an idiot I don’t care.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“To all viewers but yourself, what matters is the product: the finished artwork. To you, and you alone, what matters is the process: the experience of shaping the artwork.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“By letting go of our egos and sharing our process, we allow for the possibility of people having an ongoing connection with us and our work, which helps us move more of our product”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“We’re not all artists or astronauts. A lot of us go about our work and feel like we have nothing to show for it at the end of the day.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“whatever the nature of your work, there is an art to what you do, and there are people who would be interested in that art, if only you presented it to them in the right way.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“sharing your process might actually be most valuable if the products of your work aren’t easily shared, if you’re still in the apprentice stage of your work, if you can’t just slap up a portfolio and call it a day, or if your process doesn’t necessarily lead to tangible finished products.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“No one is going to give a damn about your résumé; they want to see what you have made with your own little fingers.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“Once a day, after you’ve done your day’s work, go back to your documentation and find one little piece of your process that you can share”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“Where you are in your process will determine what that piece is. If you’re in the very early stages, share your influences and what’s inspiring you. If you’re in the middle of executing a project, write about your methods or share works in progress. If you’ve just completed a project, show the final product, share scraps from the cutting-room floor, or write about what you learned”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“The act of sharing is one of generosity—you’re putting something out there because you think it might be helpful or entertaining to someone on the other side of the screen.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“Build a good name. Keep your name clean. Don’t make compromises. Don’t worry about making a bunch of money or being successful. Be concerned with doing good work . . . and if you can build a good name, eventually that name will be its own currency.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“All it takes to uncover hidden gems is a clear eye, an open mind, and a willingness to search for inspiration in places other people aren’t willing or able to go.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“We all love things that other people think are garbage. You have to have the courage to keep loving your garbage, because what makes us unique is the diversity and breadth of our influences, the unique ways in which we mix up the parts of culture others have deemed “high” and the “low.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“When you find things you genuinely enjoy, don’t let anyone else make you feel bad about it. Don’t feel guilty about the pleasure you take in the things you enjoy. Celebrate them. When you share your taste and your influences, have the guts to own all of it. Don’t give in to the pressure to self-edit too much.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“A character wants something, goes after it despite opposition (perhaps including his own doubts), and so arrives at a win, lose, or draw.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“You get a great idea, you go through the hard work of executing the idea, and then you release the idea out into the world, coming to a win, lose, or draw. Sometimes the idea succeeds, sometimes it fails, and more often than not, it does nothing at all.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“A good pitch is set up in three acts: The first act is the past, the second act is the present, and the third act is the future.”
“The first act is where you’ve been—what you want, how you came to want it, and what you’ve done so far to get it.”
“The second act is where you are now in your work and how you’ve worked hard and used up most of your resources. The third act is where you’re going, and how exactly the person you’re pitching can help you get there. ”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“Think about what you can share from your process that would inform the people you’re trying to reach. Have you learned a craft? What are your techniques? Are you skilled at using certain tools and materials? What kind of knowledge comes along with your job?”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“The minute you learn something, turn around and teach it to others. Share your reading list. Point to helpful reference materials. Create some tutorials and post them online. Use pictures, words, and video. Take people step-by-step through part of your process. As blogger Kathy Sierra says, “Make people better at something they want to be better at.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“Teaching people doesn’t subtract value from what you do, it actually adds to it. When you teach someone how to do your work, you are, in effect, generating more interest in your work. People feel closer to your work because you’re letting them in on what you know.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“Don’t talk to people you don’t want to talk to, and don’t talk about stuff you don’t want to talk about.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“life is all about “who you know.” But who you know is largely dependent on who you are and what you do, and the people you know can’t do anything for you if you’re not doing good work.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“Make stuff you love and talk about stuff you love and you’ll attract people who love that kind of stuff. It’s that simple.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“Try new things. If an opportunity comes along that will allow you to do more of the kind of work you want to do, say Yes. If an opportunity comes along that would mean more money, but less of the kind of work you want to do, say No.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“You avoid stalling out in your career by never losing momentum.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“Instead of taking a break in between projects, waiting for feedback, and worrying about what’s next, use the end of one project to light up the next one. ”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“Just do the work that’s in front of you, and when it’s finished, ask yourself what you missed, what you could’ve done better, or what you couldn’t get to, and jump right into the next project.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“When you throw out old work, what you’re really doing is making room for new work.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>“Look for something new to learn, and when you find it, dedicate yourself to learning it out in the open. Document your progress and share as you go so that others can learn along with you. Show your work, and when the right people show up, pay close attention to them, because they’ll have a lot to show you.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Anything You Want by Derek Sivers</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/essays/book-notes-anything-you-want-by-derek-sivers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 10:00:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/essays/book-notes-anything-you-want-by-derek-sivers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t be on your deathbed someday, having squandered your one chance at life, full of regret because you pursued little distractions instead of big dreams.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Once you&amp;rsquo;ve got a hit, suddenly all the locked doors open wide. People love the hit so much that it seems to promote itself. Instead of trying to create demand, you&amp;rsquo;re managing the huge demand&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Success comes from persistently improving and inventing, not from persistently doing what&amp;rsquo;s not working.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>We all have lots of ideas, creations, and projects. When you present one to the world, and it&amp;rsquo;s not a hit, don&amp;rsquo;t keep pushing it as-is. Instead, get back to improving and inventing.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Present each new idea or improvement to the world. If multiple people are saying, “Wow! Yes! I need this! I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to pay you to do this!” then you should probably do it. But if the response is anything less, don&amp;rsquo;t pursue it.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t waste years fighting uphill battles against locked doors. Improve or invent until you get that huge response.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>No “yes.” Either “HELL YEAH!” or “no.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re not saying “HELL YEAH!” about something, say “no.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>When deciding whether to do something, if you feel anything less than “Wow! That would be amazing! Absolutely! Hell yeah!”—then say “no.”&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re all busy. We&amp;rsquo;ve all taken on too much. Saying yes to less is the way out.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Start now. No funding needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>If you want to be useful, you can always start now, with only 1 percent of what you have in your grand vision. It&amp;rsquo;ll be a humble prototype version of your grand vision, but you&amp;rsquo;ll be in the game. You&amp;rsquo;ll be ahead of the rest, because you actually started, while others are waiting for the finish line to magically appear at the starting line.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Starting small puts 100 percent of your energy on actually solving real problems for real people. It gives you a stronger foundation to grow from. It eliminates the friction of big infrastructure and gets right to the point. And it will let you change your plan in an instant, as you&amp;rsquo;re working closely with those first customers telling you what they really need.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>So no, your idea doesn&amp;rsquo;t need funding to start. (You also don&amp;rsquo;t need an MBA, a particular big client, a certain person&amp;rsquo;s endorsement, a lucky break, or any other common excuse not to start.)&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>You need to confidently exclude people, and proudly say what you&amp;rsquo;re not. By doing so, you will win the hearts of the people you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Are you helping people? Are they happy? Are you happy? Are you profitable? Isn&amp;rsquo;t that enough?
How do you grade yourself?&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>How do you grade yourself?
It&amp;rsquo;s important to know in advance, to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re staying focused on what&amp;rsquo;s honestly important to you, instead of doing what others think you should.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>People fall in love with people who won&amp;rsquo;t give them the time of day.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>If you set up your business like you don&amp;rsquo;t need the money, people are happier to pay you.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>When someone&amp;rsquo;s doing something for love, being generous instead of stingy, trusting instead of fearful, it triggers this law: We want to give to those who give.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s another Tao of business: Set up your business like you don&amp;rsquo;t need the money, and it&amp;rsquo;ll likely come your way.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>But no matter what business you&amp;rsquo;re in, it&amp;rsquo;s good to prepare for what would happen if business doubled.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>You might get bigger faster and make millions if you outsourced everything to the experts. But what&amp;rsquo;s the point of getting bigger and making millions? To be happy, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>In the end, it&amp;rsquo;s about what you want to be, not what you want to have.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>To have something (a finished recording, a business, or millions of dollars) is the means, not the end. To be something (a good singer, a skilled entrepreneur, or just plain happy) is the real point.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>When you sign up to run a marathon, you don&amp;rsquo;t want a taxi to take you to the finish line.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>To be a true business owner, make sure you could leave for a year, and when you came back, your business would be doing better than when you left.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Never forget that you can make your role anything you want it to be.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Anything you hate to do, someone else loves. So find that person and let him do it.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>For me, I loved sitting alone and programming, writing, planning, and inventing. Thinking of ideas and making them happen. This makes me happy, not business deals or management. So I found someone who liked doing business deals and put him in charge of all that.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Delegate, but don&amp;rsquo;t abdicate.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Just pay close attention to what excites you and what drains you. Pay close attention to when you&amp;rsquo;re being the real you and when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to impress an invisible jury.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>