<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>books on Saikat Kumar Dey</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/categories/books/</link><description>Recent content in books on Saikat Kumar Dey</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</managingEditor><webMaster>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 23:35:55 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saikatkumardey.com/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Life Is Short and So Is This Book</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/10-life-is-short-and-so-is-this-book/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 23:35:55 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/10-life-is-short-and-so-is-this-book/</guid><description>The best part about the book is that it&amp;rsquo;s short and isn&amp;rsquo;t filled with fluff. Almost everything in this book is common sense found in most self-help books. But common sense isn&amp;rsquo;t common right? We need reminders to keep us on our path. This is the book that aggregates the advice found in most self-help books.
Here are some of the points that resonated with me:
people who are most productive tend to say no to things that are unimportant to them and focus on what they believe matters.</description></item><item><title>Show Your Work by Austin Kleon</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/book-notes-show-your-work-by-austin-kleon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 10:01:12 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/book-notes-show-your-work-by-austin-kleon/</guid><description>“Find a scenius, pay attention to what others are sharing, and then start taking note of what they’re not sharing. Be on the lookout for voids that you can fill with your own efforts, no matter how bad they are at first. Don’t worry, for now, about how you’ll make money or a career off it. Forget about being an expert or a professional, and wear your amateurism (your heart, your love) on your sleeve.</description></item><item><title>Anything You Want by Derek Sivers</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/book-notes-anything-you-want-by-derek-sivers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 10:00:34 +0530</pubDate><author>sample@gmail.com (Saikat Kumar Dey)</author><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/post/book-notes-anything-you-want-by-derek-sivers/</guid><description>Don&amp;rsquo;t be on your deathbed someday, having squandered your one chance at life, full of regret because you pursued little distractions instead of big dreams.
Once you&amp;rsquo;ve got a hit, suddenly all the locked doors open wide. People love the hit so much that it seems to promote itself. Instead of trying to create demand, you&amp;rsquo;re managing the huge demand
Success comes from persistently improving and inventing, not from persistently doing what&amp;rsquo;s not working.</description></item></channel></rss>