<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>daily on Saikat Kumar Dey</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/categories/daily/</link><description>daily</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 11:15:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saikatkumardey.com/categories/daily/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating a Personal Blog with Hugo: A Step-by-Step Guide</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/personal-blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 11:15:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/personal-blog/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction-to-personal-blogs">Introduction to personal blogs&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Personal blogs are a great way for individuals to share their thoughts, experiences, and expertise with the world. Not only do personal blogs provide a platform for self-expression, but they can also be a valuable tool for networking and building a personal brand. In this post, we will discuss how to set up a personal blog using Hugo, GitHub Pages, and Cloudflare.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-hugo">What is Hugo?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Hugo is a static site generator that makes it easy to create and manage a website or blog. It is known for its speed and flexibility, making it a popular choice among bloggers and web developers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="setting-up-hugo-on-your-local-machine">Setting up Hugo on your local machine&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before we can start using Hugo, we need to install it on our local machine. To do this, follow these steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Download the latest version of Hugo from the &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/">official website&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Install Hugo according to the instructions for your operating system.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Verify that Hugo is installed correctly by running the following command in your terminal: &lt;code>hugo version&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Once Hugo is installed, we are ready to create our blog!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="creating-a-new-hugo-site-and-adding-content">Creating a new Hugo site and adding content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To create a new Hugo site, run the following command in your terminal: &lt;code>hugo new site {your-site-name}&lt;/code>. This will create a new directory with the specified name and initialize it with the necessary files and folders for a Hugo site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next, navigate to the new directory and add some content to your site. Hugo uses markdown syntax for formatting content, so you can create new pages and posts using markdown files. For example, to create a new blog post, run the following command: &lt;code>hugo new post/{your-post-name}.md&lt;/code>. This will create a new markdown file in the &lt;code>/content/post&lt;/code> directory of your Hugo site, where you can add the content for your post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you have added some content to your site, you can preview it locally by running the &lt;code>hugo server&lt;/code> command. This will start a local development server that you can access at &lt;code>http://localhost:1313&lt;/code> to see your site in action.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hosting-your-hugo-site-on-github-pages">Hosting your Hugo site on GitHub Pages&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>GitHub Pages is a free hosting service provided by GitHub that allows you to host static websites directly from a GitHub repository. This makes it a perfect fit for hosting Hugo sites, as Hugo generates static HTML files for your content.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To host your Hugo site on GitHub Pages, follow these steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Create a new repository on GitHub and give it the same name as your Hugo site.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Push your Hugo site to the new repository. You can do this by running the following commands in your terminal:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>git init
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>git add .
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>git commit -m &amp;#34;Initial commit&amp;#34;
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>git remote add origin {your-github-repo-url}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>git push -u origin master
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>In the settings of your GitHub repository, go to the &amp;ldquo;GitHub Pages&amp;rdquo; section and select the &amp;ldquo;master branch&amp;rdquo; as the source for your site.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Once you have configured GitHub Pages, your Hugo site will be live at the URL provided in the &amp;ldquo;GitHub Pages&amp;rdquo; section. You can continue to make changes to your site and push them to the repository to update the live version.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="configuring-a-custom-domain-with-cloudflare">Configuring a custom domain with Cloudflare&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By default, your Hugo site will be accessible at a URL in the form of &lt;code>https://{your-github-username}.github.io/{your-site-name}&lt;/code>. If you want to use your own custom domain, you can do so by using Cloudflare.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cloudflare is a web performance and security company that offers a range of services, including DNS management and SSL/TLS encryption. By using Cloudflare, you can easily point your custom domain to your Hugo site hosted on GitHub Pages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To configure a custom domain with Cloudflare, follow these steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Sign up for a free Cloudflare account and add your domain to your account.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the DNS settings of your domain, add a new &amp;ldquo;CNAME&amp;rdquo; record that points to the URL of your Hugo site on GitHub Pages. For example, if your site is hosted at &lt;code>https://{your-github-username}.github.io/{your-site-name}&lt;/code>, your CNAME record should have the value &lt;code>{your-github-username}.github.io&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Update the nameservers for your domain to the ones provided by Cloudflare. This will allow Cloudflare to manage the DNS for your domain.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once your DNS settings have propagated, your custom domain should&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="adding-ssltls-security-with-cloudflare">Adding SSL/TLS security with Cloudflare&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By default, your Hugo site hosted on GitHub Pages will be accessible over a secure HTTPS connection. However, you can improve the security of your site even further by using an SSL/TLS certificate from Cloudflare.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To add SSL/TLS security to your Hugo site, follow these steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In the &amp;ldquo;Crypto&amp;rdquo; settings of your domain on Cloudflare, select the &amp;ldquo;Full&amp;rdquo; SSL option. This will enable SSL/TLS encryption for your site and automatically issue an SSL/TLS certificate from Cloudflare.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the &amp;ldquo;Page Rules&amp;rdquo; settings of your domain, create a new rule to redirect all HTTP traffic to HTTPS. This will ensure that all visitors to your site are automatically redirected to the secure HTTPS version.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Once you have configured SSL/TLS with Cloudflare, your Hugo site will be accessible over a secure HTTPS connection using your custom domain.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="conclusion-and-next-steps-for-customizing-your-hugo-blog">Conclusion and next steps for customizing your Hugo blog&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this post, we have covered the steps for setting up a personal blog using Hugo, GitHub Pages, and Cloudflare. You now have a fast and secure blog that you can customize to your heart&amp;rsquo;s content.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some possible next steps for customizing your Hugo blog include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Choosing a theme from the &lt;a href="https://themes.gohugo.io/">Hugo themes&lt;/a> library to give your site a unique look and feel.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adding additional functionality to your site using Hugo&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/getting-started/extended/">extended version&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/">shortcodes&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integrating your blog with social media and other online platforms using the &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/hugo-pipes/">Hugo Pipes&lt;/a> feature.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>With these tools and resources, you can take your Hugo blog to the next level and create a truly unique and engaging online presence.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In conclusion, setting up a personal blog with Hugo can be a great way to share your thoughts, ideas, and writing with the world. With its intuitive interface and powerful features, Hugo makes it easy to create and customize a professional-looking blog. By following the steps outlined in this post, you can quickly set up Hugo on your local machine, create a new site, add content, and host it on GitHub Pages. Additionally, you can use Cloudflare to configure a custom domain and add SSL/TLS security to your site. Overall, using Hugo to create your own personal blog can be a fun and rewarding experience that can help you share your voice with the world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beyond F1: using the Fbeta_score for better model evaluation</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/fbeta/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 21:08:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/fbeta/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hey everyone!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today I want to talk about a little-known evaluation metric: Fbeta_score.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with machine learning, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard of F1 score. It&amp;rsquo;s a common metric used to evaluate the performance of classification models, and it&amp;rsquo;s defined as the harmonic mean of precision and recall. This is great for a lot of tasks, but there are some situations where F1 score might not be the best choice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enter Fbeta_score. It&amp;rsquo;s similar to F1 score, but it allows you to adjust the balance between precision and recall by changing the value of beta. This can be useful in situations where you want to emphasize one of these metrics over the other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, let&amp;rsquo;s say you&amp;rsquo;re training a model to predict whether an image contains a cat or a dog. If you&amp;rsquo;re using F1 score, you&amp;rsquo;re treating precision and recall equally, but what if you want to put more emphasis on recall? This is where Fbeta_score comes in handy. By setting beta to a value greater than 1, you can increase the weight of recall in the metric, and by setting it to a value less than 1, you can decrease the weight of recall.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#000">Fbeta_score&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000">=&lt;/span> (&lt;span style="color:#1c01ce">1&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000">+&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000">beta&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000">^&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#1c01ce">2&lt;/span>) &lt;span style="color:#000">*&lt;/span> (&lt;span style="color:#000">precision&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000">*&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000">recall&lt;/span>) &lt;span style="color:#000">/&lt;/span> (&lt;span style="color:#000">beta&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000">^&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#1c01ce">2&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000">*&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000">precision&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000">+&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000">recall&lt;/span>)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>where precision is the fraction of true positives over the sum of true positives and false positives, and recall is the fraction of true positives over the sum of true positives and false negatives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>How to choose a beta?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>beta = 1&lt;/strong>
When beta=1, the Fbeta_score is equivalent to the F1 score, which treats precision and recall equally. This is a good default value to use if you don&amp;rsquo;t have any specific preferences or requirements regarding the balance between precision and recall.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>beta &amp;lt; 1&lt;/strong>
If you want to emphasize precision over recall, you can use a value of beta less than 1. For example, setting beta=0.5 will give precision twice as much weight as recall in the metric. This can be useful if you want to minimize the number of false positives, or if the cost of a false positive is higher than the cost of a false negative.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>beta &amp;gt; 1&lt;/strong>
On the other hand, if you want to emphasize recall over precision, you can use a value of beta greater than 1. For example, setting beta=2 will give recall twice as much weight as precision in the metric. This can be useful if you want to maximize the number of true positives, or if the cost of a false negative is higher than the cost of a false positive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In general, the best value of beta to use will depend on the specific goals and requirements of the task at hand. By experimenting with different values of beta, you can find the setting that produces the best results for your specific dataset and task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s how to use Fbeta_score in Python:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-python" data-lang="python">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a90d91">from&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000">sklearn.metrics&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a90d91">import&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000">fbeta_score&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#177500"># Generate some predictions&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#000">y_pred&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000">=&lt;/span> [&lt;span style="color:#1c01ce">1&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#1c01ce">0&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#1c01ce">1&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#1c01ce">1&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#1c01ce">0&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#1c01ce">0&lt;/span>]
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#177500"># Compute the Fbeta_score&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#000">fbeta_score&lt;/span>(&lt;span style="color:#000">y_true&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#000">y_pred&lt;/span>, &lt;span style="color:#000">beta&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#1c01ce">1.0&lt;/span>)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>In the code above, y_pred is a list of binary predictions, and y_true is a list of ground-truth labels. We can then use the fbeta_score function from scikit-learn to compute the Fbeta_score. By default, this will compute the F1 score (i.e. beta=1.0), but you can adjust the value of beta to change the balance between precision and recall.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to love what you do?</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/15/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 09:40:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/15/</guid><description>&lt;p>Finding the work you love can often seem like a daunting task, but there&amp;rsquo;s no secret ingredient to it. Instead, the key is to simply start producing. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a writer, an artist, a musician, or anything else, the most important thing is to just get started and begin creating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first, it&amp;rsquo;s okay to focus on quantity rather than quality. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about making everything perfect from the beginning – just keep producing and putting yourself out there. As you continue to create, you will naturally start to get better at it. And as you improve, you will begin to find more and more enjoyment in the work itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s important to remember that finding the work you love isn&amp;rsquo;t something that happens overnight. It takes time and effort to develop your skills and find your passion. But by simply starting to produce and focusing on improving, you will gradually start to love the work you&amp;rsquo;re doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So don&amp;rsquo;t worry about trying to find that elusive secret ingredient – just start creating and let the love for your work develop naturally over time. Keep producing, keep improving, and eventually you will find the work that truly brings you joy and fulfillment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Walking helps you solve difficult bugs</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/14-walk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 19:26:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/14-walk/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re a programmer, you know how frustrating it can be to come across a difficult bug. These pesky little issues can derail your entire day, leaving you feeling frustrated and stuck. But did you know that going for a walk can actually help you solve these difficult bugs?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s true – walking helps you think better. When you&amp;rsquo;re stuck on a problem, your mind tends to get stuck in a rut, going over the same information again and again. But when you take a walk, you give your mind a chance to wander and think about the problem in a new way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://news.stanford.edu/2014/04/24/walking-vs-sitting-042414/">Research&lt;/a> has shown that walking can help to boost creativity and problem-solving skills. One &lt;a href="https://www.apa.org/pubs/journals/releases/xlm-a0036577.pdf">study&lt;/a> even found that people who walked while brainstorming came up with more creative ideas than those who sat down. So the next time you&amp;rsquo;re stuck on a difficult bug, go for a walk and see if it helps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But why does walking help you think better? It&amp;rsquo;s all thanks to the way that our brains work. When we&amp;rsquo;re walking, our brains go into a state of &amp;ldquo;transient hypofrontality,&amp;rdquo; which means that the prefrontal cortex – the part of the brain responsible for logical thinking and decision-making – becomes less active. This allows our minds to wander and come up with new ideas and solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So the next time you&amp;rsquo;re struggling with a difficult bug, don&amp;rsquo;t just sit there and stare at your screen. Get up and go for a walk. Not only will it help you clear your mind, but it can also help you come up with new and creative solutions to even the most difficult problems. Happy coding!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Brave Dark Mode</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/13-brave-dark-mode/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 12:09:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/13-brave-dark-mode/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dark mode is all the rage these days, and for good reason. Not only does it look sleek and stylish, but it can also help to reduce eye strain and save battery life on devices with OLED screens. But not all browsers support dark mode by default, leaving many users to rely on extensions to enable the feature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, using an extension can come with its own set of challenges. Some users may be hesitant to use an extension due to privacy concerns, or because they simply don&amp;rsquo;t want to clutter their browser with additional software. So, what&amp;rsquo;s the solution?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re using the Brave browser, you can easily enable dark mode without having to install any extensions. Simply go to brave://flags/#enable-force-dark and &amp;ldquo;Enable&amp;rdquo; the option. That&amp;rsquo;s it – no need to install any additional software or compromise your privacy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you&amp;rsquo;ve enabled dark mode in Brave, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to enjoy all the benefits of the feature without worrying about extensions. You&amp;rsquo;ll be able to reduce eye strain, save battery life, and enjoy a sleek and stylish browsing experience. So if you&amp;rsquo;re a Brave user looking to enable dark mode, give this simple method a try – you won&amp;rsquo;t be disappointed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Best of Reddit</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/11-best-of-reddit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 21:22:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/11-best-of-reddit/</guid><description>&lt;p>I love reddit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s so much fun to learn from people from all over the world who are kind enough to unconditionally share their experiences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IMO, the best resources are buried deep inside reddit comments that could be discovered if you&amp;rsquo;re hungry enough!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are the best content I discovered so far:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/kaidomac/">r/kaidomac&lt;/a>: subreddit for aggregating knowledge from user &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/kaidomac/">u/kaidomac&lt;/a>, managed by the author himself. Some of his best posts:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/kaidomac/comments/rqyk6a/the_wpp_approach_to_planning_out_your_day/">The WPP Approach to planning out your day
&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/IWantToLearn/comments/qg3thy/deleted_by_user/hi5ex16/?context=3">Life planning&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/bodyweightfitness/comments/d0rxv6/muscle_growth/ezebxg9/?context=3">Macros tutorial&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/theXeffect/">r/theXeffect&lt;/a>: People here are on a 50-day journey to create/break one or more habits by simply making a 7x7 grid on a card and crossing off each day with a fat-ass felt marker, because your willpower is like a muscle, and it gets stronger and stronger as you exercise it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I will continue to update this as I discover new items.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Life Is Short and So Is This Book</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/10-life-is-short-and-so-is-this-book/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 23:35:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/10-life-is-short-and-so-is-this-book/</guid><description>&lt;p>The best part about the book is that it&amp;rsquo;s short and isn&amp;rsquo;t filled with fluff.
Almost everything in this book is common sense found in most self-help books.
But common sense isn&amp;rsquo;t common right? We need reminders to keep us on our path. This is the book that aggregates the advice found in most self-help books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are some of the points that resonated with me:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>people who are most productive tend to say no to things that are unimportant to them and focus on what they believe matters.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The fear of death follows from the fear of life. A man who lives fully is prepared to die at any time.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I’ve found the only way people have the stamina to outwork others, year after year, is when they love what they do.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ideally, you want a job you’d do even if you weren’t paid to do it. That’s not an economic reality for most of us, but it’s the right goal to shoot for. If you can get paid to do what you perceive as play, you have a great job.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To make changes in your life, focus on taking small steps in the right direction. Whether you want to change your health, your job, or your relationship, you can’t do it overnight. And you can’t become great at anything without a lot of repeated practice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to start a business, write a book, invent some new device, learn to play an instrument, get better at a sport, or be a good parent. Remember: take small steps. They work. Big steps often don’t. Over time, small steps add up, and you end up in a different place.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Secret of Success by Mark Twain</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/9-secret-of-success-by-mark-twain/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:24:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/9-secret-of-success-by-mark-twain/</guid><description>&lt;p>In today&amp;rsquo;s world, it can often feel like there are so many things to do and so little time to do them. It can be overwhelming to think about all the tasks and responsibilities that we have, and it can be difficult to know where to even begin. But as the famous author Marc Twain once said,&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The secret of getting ahead is getting started. The secret of getting started is breaking your complex overwhelming tasks into small manageable tasks, and starting on the first one.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In other words, the key to success is simply to take that first step. It can be intimidating to tackle a large and complex task, but by breaking it down into smaller, manageable pieces, it becomes much more manageable. And once you&amp;rsquo;ve taken that first step, the rest will start to fall into place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This quote is a great reminder that we don&amp;rsquo;t have to be perfect from the start. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to start small and work our way up – in fact, it&amp;rsquo;s the best way to make progress. So the next time you&amp;rsquo;re feeling overwhelmed by a big project or task, remember Marc Twain&amp;rsquo;s words and just start on the first step. You&amp;rsquo;ll be amazed at how much you can accomplish when you simply get started.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>pre-commit hooks</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/8-pre-commit-hooks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 23:34:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/8-pre-commit-hooks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Code smells should be identified before they&amp;rsquo;re pushed committed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://pre-commit.com/">pre-commit&lt;/a> hooks allow you to define a standard for your codebase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry if the latest PR follows the &lt;a href="https://peps.python.org/pep-0008/">PEP 8&lt;/a> conventions. Simply add a &lt;a href="https://github.com/PyCQA/flake8">flake8&lt;/a> hook to your pre-commit config file. Even better, add a &lt;a href="https://github.com/psf/black">black&lt;/a> config to ensure your code formatting is PEP 8 compliant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Accidentally added a large-file to staging? No problem, pre-commit hooks will point it out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Forgot to remove debug statements in your latest patch? pre-commit hooks got you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Forgot to add a huge file from staging? pre-commit hook will help you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes we commit massive jupyter notebooks (due to output) which makes the repository heavy &amp;amp; difficult to work with. pre-commit hooks could automatically strip the output from our notebooks before you commit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>pre-commit hooks will prevent anyone from committing changes to your code-base with such known issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It will allow the reviewers to focus on core contribution of a pull-request instead of trivial issues which could be avoided.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are you waiting for ? Go get yourself some &lt;a href="https://pre-commit.com/">pre-commit&lt;/a> hooks for your freshly minted repository!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Importance of Focusing on One Thing at a Time</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/6-relax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 10:43:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/6-relax/</guid><description>&lt;p>When it feels like the world is pulling us in a million different directions, it can be easy to become overwhelmed and stressed. We may feel like we need to multitask and tackle everything at once, but this can often be counterproductive. Instead, it&amp;rsquo;s important to take a step back and focus on one thing at a time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a common misconception that multitasking is a sign of productivity. In reality, multitasking can actually decrease our productivity and make it more difficult for us to complete tasks effectively. When we try to do too many things at once, our brains become overwhelmed and we end up doing a mediocre job on each task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, focusing on one thing at a time allows us to concentrate and give our full attention to the task at hand. This allows us to complete tasks more efficiently and with a higher level of quality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to increasing our productivity, focusing on one thing at a time also has the added benefit of bringing us inner peace. When we&amp;rsquo;re constantly multitasking and trying to do a million things at once, we can become anxious and stressed. By focusing on one thing at a time, we can let go of that stress and find a sense of calm and clarity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So next time you&amp;rsquo;re feeling pulled in a million different directions, take a step back and breathe. Instead of trying to multitask, focus on one thing at a time and delegate the rest. Not only will this increase your productivity, but it will also bring you inner peace. Remember, nothing is more important than taking care of yourself and finding inner peace.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>