<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Saikat Kumar Dey</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/</link><description>Saikat Kumar Dey</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 11:15:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saikatkumardey.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Best of Reddit</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/11-best-of-reddit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 21:22:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/11-best-of-reddit/</guid><description>&lt;p>I love reddit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s so much fun to learn from people from all over the world who are kind enough to unconditionally share their experiences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IMO, the best resources are buried deep inside reddit comments that could be discovered if you&amp;rsquo;re hungry enough!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are the best content I discovered so far:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/kaidomac/">r/kaidomac&lt;/a>: subreddit for aggregating knowledge from user &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/kaidomac/">u/kaidomac&lt;/a>, managed by the author himself. Some of his best posts:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/kaidomac/comments/rqyk6a/the_wpp_approach_to_planning_out_your_day/">The WPP Approach to planning out your day
&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/IWantToLearn/comments/qg3thy/deleted_by_user/hi5ex16/?context=3">Life planning&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/bodyweightfitness/comments/d0rxv6/muscle_growth/ezebxg9/?context=3">Macros tutorial&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/theXeffect/">r/theXeffect&lt;/a>: People here are on a 50-day journey to create/break one or more habits by simply making a 7x7 grid on a card and crossing off each day with a fat-ass felt marker, because your willpower is like a muscle, and it gets stronger and stronger as you exercise it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I will continue to update this as I discover new items.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Life Is Short and So Is This Book</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/10-life-is-short-and-so-is-this-book/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 23:35:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/10-life-is-short-and-so-is-this-book/</guid><description>&lt;p>The best part about the book is that it&amp;rsquo;s short and isn&amp;rsquo;t filled with fluff.
Almost everything in this book is common sense found in most self-help books.
But common sense isn&amp;rsquo;t common right? We need reminders to keep us on our path. This is the book that aggregates the advice found in most self-help books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are some of the points that resonated with me:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>people who are most productive tend to say no to things that are unimportant to them and focus on what they believe matters.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The fear of death follows from the fear of life. A man who lives fully is prepared to die at any time.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I’ve found the only way people have the stamina to outwork others, year after year, is when they love what they do.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ideally, you want a job you’d do even if you weren’t paid to do it. That’s not an economic reality for most of us, but it’s the right goal to shoot for. If you can get paid to do what you perceive as play, you have a great job.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To make changes in your life, focus on taking small steps in the right direction. Whether you want to change your health, your job, or your relationship, you can’t do it overnight. And you can’t become great at anything without a lot of repeated practice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to start a business, write a book, invent some new device, learn to play an instrument, get better at a sport, or be a good parent. Remember: take small steps. They work. Big steps often don’t. Over time, small steps add up, and you end up in a different place.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Secret of Success by Mark Twain</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/9-secret-of-success-by-mark-twain/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:24:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/9-secret-of-success-by-mark-twain/</guid><description>&lt;p>In today&amp;rsquo;s world, it can often feel like there are so many things to do and so little time to do them. It can be overwhelming to think about all the tasks and responsibilities that we have, and it can be difficult to know where to even begin. But as the famous author Marc Twain once said,&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The secret of getting ahead is getting started. The secret of getting started is breaking your complex overwhelming tasks into small manageable tasks, and starting on the first one.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In other words, the key to success is simply to take that first step. It can be intimidating to tackle a large and complex task, but by breaking it down into smaller, manageable pieces, it becomes much more manageable. And once you&amp;rsquo;ve taken that first step, the rest will start to fall into place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This quote is a great reminder that we don&amp;rsquo;t have to be perfect from the start. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to start small and work our way up – in fact, it&amp;rsquo;s the best way to make progress. So the next time you&amp;rsquo;re feeling overwhelmed by a big project or task, remember Marc Twain&amp;rsquo;s words and just start on the first step. You&amp;rsquo;ll be amazed at how much you can accomplish when you simply get started.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>pre-commit hooks</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/8-pre-commit-hooks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 23:34:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/8-pre-commit-hooks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Code smells should be identified before they&amp;rsquo;re pushed committed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://pre-commit.com/">pre-commit&lt;/a> hooks allow you to define a standard for your codebase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry if the latest PR follows the &lt;a href="https://peps.python.org/pep-0008/">PEP 8&lt;/a> conventions. Simply add a &lt;a href="https://github.com/PyCQA/flake8">flake8&lt;/a> hook to your pre-commit config file. Even better, add a &lt;a href="https://github.com/psf/black">black&lt;/a> config to ensure your code formatting is PEP 8 compliant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Accidentally added a large-file to staging? No problem, pre-commit hooks will point it out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Forgot to remove debug statements in your latest patch? pre-commit hooks got you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Forgot to add a huge file from staging? pre-commit hook will help you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes we commit massive jupyter notebooks (due to output) which makes the repository heavy &amp;amp; difficult to work with. pre-commit hooks could automatically strip the output from our notebooks before you commit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>pre-commit hooks will prevent anyone from committing changes to your code-base with such known issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It will allow the reviewers to focus on core contribution of a pull-request instead of trivial issues which could be avoided.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are you waiting for ? Go get yourself some &lt;a href="https://pre-commit.com/">pre-commit&lt;/a> hooks for your freshly minted repository!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Importance of Focusing on One Thing at a Time</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/6-relax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 10:43:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/6-relax/</guid><description>&lt;p>When it feels like the world is pulling us in a million different directions, it can be easy to become overwhelmed and stressed. We may feel like we need to multitask and tackle everything at once, but this can often be counterproductive. Instead, it&amp;rsquo;s important to take a step back and focus on one thing at a time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a common misconception that multitasking is a sign of productivity. In reality, multitasking can actually decrease our productivity and make it more difficult for us to complete tasks effectively. When we try to do too many things at once, our brains become overwhelmed and we end up doing a mediocre job on each task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, focusing on one thing at a time allows us to concentrate and give our full attention to the task at hand. This allows us to complete tasks more efficiently and with a higher level of quality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to increasing our productivity, focusing on one thing at a time also has the added benefit of bringing us inner peace. When we&amp;rsquo;re constantly multitasking and trying to do a million things at once, we can become anxious and stressed. By focusing on one thing at a time, we can let go of that stress and find a sense of calm and clarity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So next time you&amp;rsquo;re feeling pulled in a million different directions, take a step back and breathe. Instead of trying to multitask, focus on one thing at a time and delegate the rest. Not only will this increase your productivity, but it will also bring you inner peace. Remember, nothing is more important than taking care of yourself and finding inner peace.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Own Your Content</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/5-own-your-content/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:54:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/5-own-your-content/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over a decade or so, I have written blog posts in different platforms scattered all over the Internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What happens when those companies go out of business? All of your data would be lost unless you&amp;rsquo;ve kept a backup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sive.rs/plaintext">Derek Sivers&lt;/a> recommends keeping your content on text files. Text files are cross-platform &amp;amp; easy to manage. You could easily convert them to the format of your choice. You do not need the internet to access your files. Sure, online platforms might provide a better UI. However, you don&amp;rsquo;t really need the distraction while putting down your raw thoughts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have many ideas jotted down across multiple platforms, apps and yes, text files on my devices. From now on, I will use this website as my own digital garden to keep it all. I will start gathering all my posts from the past scattered across different platforms and share them in this space.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Never Too Late: The Inspiring Story of Van Gogh</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/4-never-too-late/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:40:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/4-never-too-late/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have you ever felt like it&amp;rsquo;s too late to pursue your dreams? Perhaps you feel like you&amp;rsquo;re too old, or you&amp;rsquo;ve missed your chance. If so, it&amp;rsquo;s time to reconsider. The story of Van Gogh is a perfect example of how it&amp;rsquo;s never too late to start something and become world-class at it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Van Gogh is one of the most famous and celebrated artists in history, known for his beautiful and unique paintings. But did you know that he didn&amp;rsquo;t start painting seriously until he was 27 years old? That&amp;rsquo;s right, it was well into his adult life before Van Gogh began pursuing his passion for art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Despite starting later in life, Van Gogh was incredibly productive. Over the course of just 10 years, he created over 2,000 artworks. And most of those were created in the last two years of his life. In just a short amount of time, Van Gogh was able to achieve incredible success and make a lasting impact on the world of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is proof that it&amp;rsquo;s never too late to start something and become world-class at it. If Van Gogh could do it, so can you. So don&amp;rsquo;t let age or any other perceived limitations hold you back. It&amp;rsquo;s never too late to pursue your dreams and make them a reality. Take inspiration from Van Gogh and start working towards your goals today. You never know what you might be capable of achieving.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Power of Consistent Investing</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/3-keep-investing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 21:03:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/3-keep-investing/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you have money to spare, it&amp;rsquo;s always a good idea to invest it. Investing can help your money grow and provide financial security for the future. But where should you invest your money? And how can you make the most of your investments? Here are some key tips to keep in mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First and foremost, don&amp;rsquo;t try to pick individual stocks. Unless you have a lot of experience and expertise in the stock market, it&amp;rsquo;s generally not a good idea to try and pick individual stocks. Instead, invest in index funds and ETFs. These types of investments are more diversified, which means they can help reduce the overall risk of your investment portfolio. And as the saying goes, &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t put all your eggs in one basket.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another important tip is to automate your investments. One of the best ways to do this is through a systematic investment plan (SIP). A SIP allows you to automatically invest a fixed amount of money at regular intervals. This can help you build a consistent investment strategy and take the emotion out of investing. Plus, it can be a convenient way to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re always investing, even when you&amp;rsquo;re busy with other things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s also important to remember that time in the market is more important than timing the market. In other words, it&amp;rsquo;s not about trying to predict when the market will go up or down. Instead, focus on building a long-term investment strategy that can help your money grow over time. And remember, the real fruit of your investments will be seen years later. So don&amp;rsquo;t be discouraged if you don&amp;rsquo;t see immediate results. Let compound interest do its thing and your investments can grow significantly over time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, don&amp;rsquo;t worry too much about the market. It&amp;rsquo;s natural to want to stay up-to-date on the latest market news and trends. But ultimately, your time is better spent focusing on being the best at what you do. And remember, when the market is down, it&amp;rsquo;s actually an opportunity to buy equity at a discount. So don&amp;rsquo;t let market fluctuations discourage you. Keep investing consistently and let your money grow over time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What I'm doing now</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/now/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:58:39 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/now/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="work">Work&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I am a Senior Data Scientist at &lt;a href="https://www.gojek.io/">Gojek&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I build real-time, low-latency computer vision models for edge devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reading">Reading&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I am currently reading &lt;em>Designing Machine Learning Systems&lt;/em> by Huyen Chip.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Thanks to &lt;a href="https://sive.rs/now">Derek Sivers&lt;/a> for sharing the idea of having a now page&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hosting on Github Pages</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/2-hosting-on-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:44:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/posts/2-hosting-on-github-pages/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Make sure you have a &lt;a href="https://github.com/saikatkumardey/saikatkumardey.github.io/blob/main/CNAME">CNAME&lt;/a> file with your custom website in it. Make sure that you have it in your &amp;ldquo;gh-pages&amp;rdquo; branch.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ensure that you have configured the CNAME in your DNS provider&amp;rsquo;s console. I am using &lt;a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/">Cloudflare&lt;/a>. So, I have configured 2 records&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>CNAME to redirect &amp;ldquo;saikatkumardey.com&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;saikatkumardey.github.io&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CNAME to redirect &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://www.saikatkumardey.com">www.saikatkumardey.com&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;saikatkumardey.github.io&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Make sure that you set the Source of your Github Pages site to be built from the gh-pages branch. Go to Settings &amp;gt; Pages &amp;gt; Source. Check if it&amp;rsquo;s set to gh-pages. This caused me a lot of pain. It&amp;rsquo;s set to &amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo; by default.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>