<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Daily on Saikat Kumar Dey</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/</link><description>Daily</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 10:25:15 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Accuracy Is a Poor evaluation Metric</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/12-accuracy-is-a-poor-error-metric/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 10:25:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/12-accuracy-is-a-poor-error-metric/</guid><description>&lt;p>For classification problems, something like Cross-entropy is a good metric for minimizing your model&amp;rsquo;s loss.
However, we need something easier to convey to the stakeholders.
Accuracy is a very easy way to show our model performances. The caveat? Accuracy would be misleading for imbalanced classes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s why.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s say that you&amp;rsquo;ve built a model for detecting cancer.
Here&amp;rsquo;s how the confusion matrix would look like for a dataset on cancer cases.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Predicted Cancer&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Predicted cancer-free&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Actual cancer cases&lt;/td>
&lt;td>10 (TP)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>5 (FN)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Actual cancer-free cases&lt;/td>
&lt;td>150 (FP)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>800 (TN)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>The dataset has 950 cancer-free patients and 15 patients with cancer.
The accuracy of the model = fraction of correct predictions = (10 + 800) / (10 + 5 + 150 + 800) = 0.84.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, the cancer cases are quite rare, so it barely has any effect on the accuracy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the model had predicted every case as cancer-free, the confusion matrix would look like the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Predicted Cancer&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Predicted cancer-free&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Actual cancer cases&lt;/td>
&lt;td>0 (TP)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>15 (FN)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Actual cancer-free cases&lt;/td>
&lt;td>0 (FP)&lt;/td>
&lt;td>950 (TN)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Accuracy = 950/(950 + 15) = 0.984%.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is not what we want to report to our stakeholders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are our options?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In such cases with class imbalance, we usually look at &lt;em>precision&lt;/em> and &lt;em>recall&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Precision&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>precision = TP/(TP + FP)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Precision is &lt;em>out of all the cancer diagnosis made by the model, how many of them actually have cancer&lt;/em>. In the first case, model predicted 165 cases as having cancer but only 15 of them actually had cancer. So, the precision is 15/165 which is quite low!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Recall&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>recall = TP/(TP/FN)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Recall is &lt;em>out of all the actual cancer cases, how many could the model detect?&lt;/em>
In the first case, model detected 15 out of 20 cancer cases. So, the recall is 15/20 = 0.75. That&amp;rsquo;s not bad!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our objective is to detect as many cancer cases as we can (TP) while minimizing the false diagnosis of cancer (FP). In other words, we want to have high recall with high precision.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All of these metrics rely on the probability threshold chosen to classify each sample as having cancer or not. If prediction probability &amp;gt; threshold, predict cancer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, if you choose 0.9 as the threshold, you might only classify cases where the model is highly confident ie, high precision. However, you might miss out on many cases at that threshold ie, low recall. Instead, if you keep 0.1 as the threshold, you might capture all the cancer cases but you&amp;rsquo;d be scaring a lot of other cancer-free patients with misdiagnosis as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By varying the probability threshold, you could check the trade-off between precision &amp;amp; recall, also called the precision-recall curve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes, precision &amp;amp; recall are combined together into one metric, called F1 score.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>F1 = 2 / (1/precision + 1/recall)
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s another variant of the precision-recall curve which is agnostic to the probability threshold selected. It&amp;rsquo;s called the ROC curve (Receiver Operating Characteristics). The area under the curve (AUC) is demonstrative of the overall model performance. AUC is useful to know how well the model is in classifying both the classes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Conclusion&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Do not use accuracy metric when there&amp;rsquo;s a class imbalance.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use F1 or ROC-AUC instead.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Reference&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/practical-machine-learning/9781098102357/">Practical Machine Learning for Computer Vision&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precision_and_recall">Precision Recall&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Receiver_operating_characteristic">ROC Curve&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Best of Reddit</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/11-best-of-reddit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 21:22:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/11-best-of-reddit/</guid><description>&lt;p>I love reddit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s so much fun to learn from people from all over the world who are kind enough to unconditionally share their experiences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>IMO, the best resources are buried deep inside reddit comments that could be discovered if you&amp;rsquo;re hungry enough!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are the best content I discovered so far:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/kaidomac/">r/kaidomac&lt;/a>: subreddit for aggregating knowledge from user &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/kaidomac/">u/kaidomac&lt;/a>, managed by the author himself. Some of his best posts:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/kaidomac/comments/rqyk6a/the_wpp_approach_to_planning_out_your_day/">The WPP Approach to planning out your day
&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/IWantToLearn/comments/qg3thy/deleted_by_user/hi5ex16/?context=3">Life planning&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/bodyweightfitness/comments/d0rxv6/muscle_growth/ezebxg9/?context=3">Macros tutorial&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/theXeffect/">r/theXeffect&lt;/a>: People here are on a 50-day journey to create/break one or more habits by simply making a 7x7 grid on a card and crossing off each day with a fat-ass felt marker, because your willpower is like a muscle, and it gets stronger and stronger as you exercise it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I will continue to update this as I discover new items.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Life Is Short and So Is This Book</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/10-life-is-short-and-so-is-this-book/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 23:35:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/10-life-is-short-and-so-is-this-book/</guid><description>&lt;p>The best part about the book is that it&amp;rsquo;s short and isn&amp;rsquo;t filled with fluff.
Almost everything in this book is common sense found in most self-help books.
But common sense isn&amp;rsquo;t common right? We need reminders to keep us on our path. This is the book that aggregates the advice found in most self-help books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are some of the points that resonated with me:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>people who are most productive tend to say no to things that are unimportant to them and focus on what they believe matters.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The fear of death follows from the fear of life. A man who lives fully is prepared to die at any time.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I’ve found the only way people have the stamina to outwork others, year after year, is when they love what they do.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ideally, you want a job you’d do even if you weren’t paid to do it. That’s not an economic reality for most of us, but it’s the right goal to shoot for. If you can get paid to do what you perceive as play, you have a great job.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To make changes in your life, focus on taking small steps in the right direction. Whether you want to change your health, your job, or your relationship, you can’t do it overnight. And you can’t become great at anything without a lot of repeated practice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to start a business, write a book, invent some new device, learn to play an instrument, get better at a sport, or be a good parent. Remember: take small steps. They work. Big steps often don’t. Over time, small steps add up, and you end up in a different place.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Secret of Success by Mark Twain</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/9-secret-of-success-by-mark-twain/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:24:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/9-secret-of-success-by-mark-twain/</guid><description>&lt;p>The secret of getting ahead is getting started. The secret of getting started is breaking your complex overwhelming tasks into small manageable tasks, and starting on the first one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>pre-commit hooks</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/8-pre-commit-hooks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 23:34:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/8-pre-commit-hooks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Code smells should be identified before they&amp;rsquo;re pushed committed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://pre-commit.com/">pre-commit&lt;/a> hooks allow you to define a standard for your codebase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry if the latest PR follows the &lt;a href="https://peps.python.org/pep-0008/">PEP 8&lt;/a> conventions. Simply add a &lt;a href="https://github.com/PyCQA/flake8">flake8&lt;/a> hook to your pre-commit config file. Even better, add a &lt;a href="https://github.com/psf/black">black&lt;/a> config to ensure your code formatting is PEP 8 compliant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Accidentally added a large-file to staging? No problem, pre-commit hooks will point it out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Forgot to remove debug statements in your latest patch? pre-commit hooks got you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Forgot to add a huge file from staging? pre-commit hook will help you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes we commit massive jupyter notebooks (due to output) which makes the repository heavy &amp;amp; difficult to work with. pre-commit hooks could automatically strip the output from our notebooks before you commit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>pre-commit hooks will prevent anyone from committing changes to your code-base with such known issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It will allow the reviewers to focus on core contribution of a pull-request instead of trivial issues which could be avoided.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are you waiting for ? Go get yourself some &lt;a href="https://pre-commit.com/">pre-commit&lt;/a> hooks for your freshly minted repository!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FIFA World Cup 2022</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/7-world-cup-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 23:06:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/7-world-cup-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>I got tickets to watch Brazil play in the FIFA World Cup 2022.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This would be a dream come true. I am super excited to watch Neymar play in a stadium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, I just need to plan the logistics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stay tuned for updates! :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Relax</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/6-relax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 10:43:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/6-relax/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some days, you&amp;rsquo;ll be pulled into so many different directions that you won&amp;rsquo;t know what to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take a step back and breathe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nothing is more important than inner peace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Focus on one and only one thing and finish that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No need to multitask. Delegate it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Own Your Content</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/5-own-your-content/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:54:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/5-own-your-content/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over a decade or so, I have written blog posts in different platforms scattered all over the Internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What happens when those companies go out of business? All of your data would be lost unless you&amp;rsquo;ve kept a backup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sive.rs/plaintext">Derek Sivers&lt;/a> recommends keeping your content on text files. Text files are cross-platform &amp;amp; easy to manage. You could easily convert them to the format of your choice. You do not need the internet to access your files. Sure, online platforms might provide a better UI. However, you don&amp;rsquo;t really need the distraction while putting down your raw thoughts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have many ideas jotted down across multiple platforms, apps and yes, text files on my devices. From now on, I will use this website as my own digital garden to keep it all. I will start gathering all my posts from the past scattered across different platforms and share them in this space.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Never Too Late</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/4-never-too-late/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:40:51 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/4-never-too-late/</guid><description>&lt;p>Van Gogh started painting seriously at 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He created over 2000 artworks over a decade, most of which were created in the last 2 years of his life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s never too late to start anything and become world class at it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Van Gogh did it. You could do it too.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Keep Investing</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/3-keep-investing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 21:03:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/3-keep-investing/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you have money to spare, invest it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the market is down, it&amp;rsquo;s giving you an opportunity to buy equity at a discount.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do not pick individual stocks. You&amp;rsquo;re not a trader. Invest into index funds &amp;amp; ETFs instead. Read up on &lt;a href="https://www.bogleheads.org/wiki/Getting_started">Bogleheads Philosophy&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Automate your investments. SIPs are the way to go. Time in the market is more important than timing the market.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The real fruit of your investments will be seen years later. Let compound interest do her thing silently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should focus on being the best at what you do. Worrying about the market is a waste of your time which could be utilised in honing your craft.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the market is up, keep buying. When the market is down, buy more.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>