<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>book on Saikat Kumar Dey</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/categories/book/</link><description>book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 23:35:55 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://saikatkumardey.com/categories/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Life Is Short and So Is This Book</title><link>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/10-life-is-short-and-so-is-this-book/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 23:35:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://saikatkumardey.com/daily/10-life-is-short-and-so-is-this-book/</guid><description>&lt;p>The best part about the book is that it&amp;rsquo;s short and isn&amp;rsquo;t filled with fluff.
Almost everything in this book is common sense found in most self-help books.
But common sense isn&amp;rsquo;t common right? We need reminders to keep us on our path. This is the book that aggregates the advice found in most self-help books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are some of the points that resonated with me:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>people who are most productive tend to say no to things that are unimportant to them and focus on what they believe matters.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The fear of death follows from the fear of life. A man who lives fully is prepared to die at any time.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I’ve found the only way people have the stamina to outwork others, year after year, is when they love what they do.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ideally, you want a job you’d do even if you weren’t paid to do it. That’s not an economic reality for most of us, but it’s the right goal to shoot for. If you can get paid to do what you perceive as play, you have a great job.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To make changes in your life, focus on taking small steps in the right direction. Whether you want to change your health, your job, or your relationship, you can’t do it overnight. And you can’t become great at anything without a lot of repeated practice.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you want to start a business, write a book, invent some new device, learn to play an instrument, get better at a sport, or be a good parent. Remember: take small steps. They work. Big steps often don’t. Over time, small steps add up, and you end up in a different place.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>